Ma Yiming.
马一鸣
Isn't she Xu Mengyu
那不是你们学校那个
from your school?
徐梦予吗
Why is she here?
她怎么来看我们打球
Be right back.
我一会儿回来
What? Where are you going?
马一鸣 你干嘛去
Leaving us 2v3?
你让我们二打三啊
Mengyu.
梦姐
You're here...?
你怎么来了
I'm stuck on my writing,
我写作遇到点瓶颈
so I figured watching hoops
来看看篮球
might spark some ideas.
找找灵感
Ma Yiming, come on back!
马一鸣 快点
You're training pretty hard.
你们训练得挺认真啊
You bet.
那当然
Our team's on fire.
我们球队那正经厉害呢
Remember that last game we played...
就上次我们比赛
Hey man, hurry!
马一鸣 快点的
Coming!
来了 来了
Mengyu, excuse me.
梦姐 我先回去了
Nice shot! Alright.
好球 撤了 撤了 撤了
Let's call it a day.
回了
Hi, Ma Mao.
师哥
Mengyu, it's you.
梦予 你来啦
I'm done here.
我刚好结束了
Wanna join me for dinner?
一起吃饭吧
Let's go.
走吧
Okay.
走
I'm off.
走了 走了
Bye.
拜拜 拜拜
Good morning, Xiaohua.
早啊 徒弟
Yeah...
早
All done with homework
作业写完了
and notes.
笔记也整理了
So bored now.
好无聊啊
Xiaohua.
小画
Got anything on your mind
你有没有什么
that you need help with?
需要我帮你解决的问题
Whether it's life stuff
不管是人生上也好
or schoolwork,
还是学业上也好
let's chat about it.
我来帮你讲讲
Nope.
没有
Kinda weird
同桌不在
without my desk buddy around.
还有点不太习惯呢
Looks like you miss me very much.
没想到你这么想我呀
Well, good thing,
那正好
I brought you some gifts.
给你带了些礼物
Sure you'll love them.
你肯定喜欢
Why are you here?
你怎么来了
Who's looking after your mom?
那你来了谁照顾阿姨啊
Someone is.
有人帮我照顾
Maybe you should take a few days off.
要不你还是休息几天吧
Now, check this one out.
别画了你先看这题
What does the given info tell us?
说由已知得出什么
We know EF is parallel to CD.
EF平行于CD
And EF...
且EF
Focus on EF.
看 EF
Class's over.
下课
Stand up.
起立
Thank you, sir.
老师再见
Are you coming with me to the hospital?
走吧 去医院看阿姨
Ling Dong's mom should be discharged today.
阿姨不是今天出院吗
Whoops.
对了
It slipped my mind.
我把这茬儿给忘了
Jinghui.
师父
Do you remember
你记得
what day it is tomorrow?
明天是什么日子吗
Of course.
我当然知道
You really do?
你居然记得
It's Saturday,
明天是一个自由的
a day of freedom
慵懒
and lounging around till noon.
可以睡到中午的周末
Been waiting five days,
我都盼了五天了
how could I forget?
你说我能不知道吗
That's not what I'm talking about.
我不是说这个
So it's a trivia question, huh?
你要考我常识问答是吧
World Oral Health Day?
国际爱牙日
Forget it, looks like you don't recall.
算了 我看你不记得
World Sleep Day?
世界睡眠日
Wrong.
不不
Come on, spill the beans.
那你好歹公布一下
What's the answer?
正确答案不是吗
Really?
真的
Yeah.
嗯
I'm pretty sure.
我很确定
Alright, let's
那我们可得
do something special.
好好搞点事情了
Mom, I'm back.
妈 我回来了
Mom?
妈
Surprise!
惊喜
Happy birthday.
生日快乐
♪Happy birthday to you♪
祝你生日快乐
We went
这是我们
all out for this.
特意给你布置的
Surprised?
惊喜吧
You guys did all this?
这些都是你们布置的
We did every single bit of it ourselves.
一个一个亲自布置的
Dong.
冬冬
Wishing you
妈妈祝你
a wonderful 18th birthday!
十八岁生日快乐
Thanks, mom.
谢谢妈妈
Okay.
走
Candles, cake, wish!
吹蜡烛 吃蛋糕 许愿
Wish and cake.
许愿 吃蛋糕了
Go.
快走
Give me your bag.
来 把书包给妈
Let's go.
走吧
Earth gravity?
万有引力
Nope, its
不对 是
the Power of Friends.
是万友引力
Let's light the candles.
来 点蜡烛
Yeah.
点蜡烛
Okay.
好
Alright, birthday star, make your wish.
那么请寿星准备许愿
They say that
都说这个
18th birthday wishes
十八岁的这个愿望
are extra lucky.
是最灵验的
I bet you're wishing to
那么我相信你的愿望
get into JU, right?
一定是考上京大
It's Ling Dong's big day.
这是凌冬的生日
Let him make his own wish.
你让他自己许
Don't mess around.
你瞎捣什么乱呀
Hey! I'm not.
我这怎么能叫瞎捣乱呢
He totally wants that.
他肯定就这么想
Right, auntie?
是不是 阿姨
Dong.
冬冬啊
I think he's right.
我觉得他们说得对
Since you three are such good friends,
你们三个是好朋友
how about wishing you all
你呢 就许个愿
get into JU
明年你们可以
next year?
一起考入京大
Auntie, you're the best!
还是阿姨想得周到啊
We're relying on you to
那我们俩能不能上京大
get us into JU.
就拜托你了
Go on.
许吧
I hope I can always
希望我能永远
be by my mom's side,
陪在妈妈身边
and that she stays healthy forever.
希望妈妈身体健康
Happy birthday.
生日快乐
Xiaohua, how dare you, huh?
小画 你能耐了是吧
Careful.
当心啊
Ms Fang.
方老师
Here's my college application form.
这是我的志愿填报单
Why?
为什么
You're the top of your grade, and
你可是全年级第一
you've won national physics comp.
全国物理竞赛又拿过奖
With your grades, getting into
以你的成绩考上京大
JU is in your pocket.
那是十拿九稳的事
Why don't you
难道你不想考
aim for the top uni?
最好的学校吗
I've made up my mind.
我已经决定好了
It's alright.
没关系
You don't have to rush it.
你不用这么快给我决定
And it's just
而且这次
a practice round,
只是模拟填报志愿
you can switch it up later.
还有的机会反悔
Ling Dong.
凌冬
You know,
你要知道
JU is
京大是多少人
a dream school for many.
梦寐以求的地方
You have the ability to get in,
可你是有这个能力的
so why would you
你为什么要放弃
give it up?
这么好的机会
And have you talked to your mom
而且你的这个选择
about your decision?
你家人知道吗
Ling Dong, may I ask if there's
凌冬 老师可以问一下
a connection between this
这个跟你这几天请假
and your recent absences?
有什么关系吗
You know I can help
如果你家里有什么困难
if you have any...
你可以跟老师
Ms Fang.
老师
Rong University is my pick.
考蓉大是我的个人选择
Alright, I won't push you.
好 我不逼你
you still have time
反正还有机会
to think it through.
你可以考虑清楚
You're... aiming for RU?
你 想考蓉大
You heard?
你都知道了
I didn't mean to.
我今天白天
It just happened.
不是故意听见的
I stumbled upon
真的是碰巧
Ms Fang and Mr Zhang
我听见
talking about how you
方老师跟张主任说
gave up JU because of
你因为你妈妈的事
your mom.
不考了
But she's
可是妈妈
out of the hospital already, right?
不是已经出院了吗
She's suffered from bad health,
我妈的身体一直不好
so I gotta stick around
少不了我要一直
and take care of her.
在身边照顾
What about your own dreams?
那你自己的梦想呢
Your life and your aspirations?
你的人生 你的梦想呢
As a kid,
我小时候
I saw my dad
亲眼看着我爸爸
get rushed to the ER,
被送进了抢救室
but he didn't make it.
但是 他没能活着出来
So when my mom
所以这次
went through
当我看着我妈妈
the same thing,
也被送进抢救室的时候
I told myself,
我就告诉我自己
I've lost my dad,
我已经失去爸爸了
not my mom too.
我不能再没有妈妈
Okay.
好
I got you back.
我支持你
You mean it?
你说真的
I mean it.
我说真的
I really thought about it,
我仔细地想了一下
if it were me,
如果换做是我的话
I'd do the same.
我肯定会做同样的决定
Don't sweat it, let's go.
别想多了 走吧
Keep up.
走吧
Mom.
妈
Dong, you're back.
冬冬回来了
I made you a bowl of noodles,
妈给你做了一碗面
come and have a taste.
快过来尝尝
Mom.
妈
The doctor said
医生不是说了
you need to rest,
让你静养嘛
but you're in the kitchen already?
你怎么还做饭
It's okay. Don't worry.
稍微动一动不碍事的
Come on, try this.
快过来 来 尝尝
See how it tastes.
快吃吃看
And some tasty treats.
还有两个可口的小菜
Mom.
妈
Is it good?
怎么样 好吃吗
Very.
好吃
How time flies.
不知不觉
Look at you, all grown up
你都长这么大了
and about to leave
马上就要上大学
for college.
离开妈妈了
Mom, I'm not leaving you.
妈 我不会离开你的
Your teacher called me,
你们老师给我打电话了
saying you picked RU.
说你填报的志愿是蓉大
Dong.
冬冬啊
It's a big deal.
这大学志愿是很重要的
You can't be so hasty.
你不能这么含糊
I don't want you
而且妈妈不希望
rushing into this decision.
你就这么草率地去决定
Dong, listen to me.
冬冬 你听妈妈说
I know you're
妈妈知道
worried about my health,
你是担心我的身体
but your future
可是你的前程
is more important.
比妈妈的身体更重要
Besides,
再说
you've always wanna
你不是一直想考
get into JU for physics.
京大物理系吗
You're so good at your studies,
你学习那么好
I know you can make it.
你肯定能考上的
And
还有
didn't you
就是上次
and your friends
你跟几个同学
have a deal about JU?
不都是已经约好了吗
Mom.
妈
But right now
可是我现在
I don't wanna aim for JU anymore.
是真的不想考京大
I just wanna be by your side.
我就想陪在你身边
That's what I truly want.
这是我的理想
This could be
可是你这样
your big regret later on.
以后肯定会后悔的
Listen.
你知道吗
It's a major life choice.
这是你一辈子的大事
All I care about
我觉得我这一辈子
in my life
最大的事
is this family
最重要的事就是这个家
and being with you.
就是能陪着你
My birthday wish was
我生日的时候许的愿望
always for your good health
就是希望你能身体健康
and for me to
希望我可以
be by your side.
一直陪在你身边
And you know me,
而且 我你还不了解吗
whether it's at RU or JU,
不管是在蓉大还是京大
I'll do well.
我都能有出息的
What? Dong.
不是 你这孩子
Why can't you
你说我好好跟你说
listen to me?
你怎么就听不进去呢
I don't wanna be
我是不想因为我
a burden to you,
拖累了你
okay?
你明白吗
Mom.
妈
Even before you were in the hospital,
在你住院之前
I'd already decided
我就已经想好
on RU.
要考蓉大了
I wanna be by your side.
我就是想陪着你
And
而且
since it's just us two in the family,
咱们家现在就剩我们俩了
I don't wanna leave you alone.
我真的不想分开
But...
可是
Mom.
妈
This is my choice.
这是我的志愿
I got my own plans.
我有我自己的想法
You want me to go to JU,
你想让我考京大
but that's not what I want.
那不是我想要的
It's what you think I want.
是你认为我想要的
Being here with you,
我认为我能陪在你身边
taking care of you,
能照顾你
that's what matters most.
这个比京大重要多了
So, mom,
所以 妈
just for this once,
就这一次
let me do it my way, okay?
听我的 好吗
I know you mean well.
我知道你是为了我好
But
可是
it's like I'm holding you back.
我总感觉是我拖累你了
This is huge,
这么大一件事情
why didn't you
你怎么不事先
talk to me about it?
跟我商量一下呢
Mom.
妈
No egg today?
今天的面怎么没蛋呀
How about a fried one?
你要吃煎蛋哪
Then I'll go...
那你等一
Stop distracting me.
你别跟我打岔
Mom.
妈
I've given this
这件事
a lot of thought,
我已经考虑很久了
it's not just a whim.
并不是一时冲动
Don't you wanna see my happy face?
难道你不想让我开心吗
But...
可是
Alright, mom.
好了 妈
I want a fried egg.
没有蛋怎么吃啊
Alright.
行
Coming right up.
你等会儿啊 马上就好
Thanks, mom.
谢谢妈
Ready.
准备了
Smile wider.
笑开心一点
One, two, three.
三 二 一
Cheese.
茄子
Wait.
等会儿
One more.
再来一下 没拍好
3, 2, 1, go!
三 二 一
Cheese!
茄子
Perfect!
可以了
What are your summer plans?
你们暑假都什么安排啊
No time for fun,
什么什么安排
gotta hit the art studio
我要去参加美术集训
every day.
每天都得上课
So miserable.
这么惨
It hurts, but it's also fulfilling.
这叫痛并快乐着
Good job.
干得漂亮
I wasn't even in the shot!
我还没拍呢
What about you?
那你呢
To take care of my mom.
在家陪我妈
And?
还有呢
Keep your studies on track.
督促你学习
Nah, thanks.
免了 谢谢
Ma Yiming.
马一鸣
What's up?
咋了
What's your plan?
暑假什么安排啊
I've got basketball training,
我篮球要训练
and I'm gonna play
然后还要去跟大学校队
in a match.
打比赛
Cheer up.
加油吧
I believe in you.
哥看好你
Don't let me down.
别给我丢人啊
I won't.
必须的
Qingtian, the long vacation is coming up.
晴天 都要放长假了
Why the sigh?
你叹什么气啊
I don't like it at all.
我一点都不喜欢放长假
I'm always alone at home.
一放假家里就我一个人
It's so boring.
别提多无聊了
If you're bored,
你要是无聊
I can hang out with you.
我可以陪你玩
No way.
我不要
All you do
你找我玩
is make me study.
不是学习就是学习
I don't wanna study during vacation.
我才不想假期学习
I'm stressed too.
我也快愁死了
During holidays,
这一放假呀
all kinds of relatives come to visit
就有各种亲戚来我家
my house.
做客
Those I know
三大姑八大姨的
and don't know,
然后认识的 不认识的
some I can't even
叫得上名的
know their names,
叫不上名的
and
还有那种
little kids...
比我还小的小孩
They would just
来了我家以后
make a mess,
又作 又闹腾
and touch my stuff.
又翻我东西
It's so annoying!
烦死了
I'll never
我就完全
have that problem.
不会有这样的困扰
Jinghui!
表哥
Li'l Su, it's really you?
苏小妹 真的是你啊
First, don't call me that.
第一 我不是苏小妹
My Chinese name is Su Xi,
我的中文名是苏夕
and my English name is Susie.
英文名Susie
I'm...
我
grown up now,
我已经长大了
so please don't
请你以后
call me that anymore.
不要再叫我苏小妹了
Second,
第二
I'm here for vacation at Grandma's house,
我是回外婆家度假的
and to visit you by the way.
顺便啊 看望一下你
Susie?
苏 苏夕
Is it really you?
真的是你啊
Who else?
那不然呢
Do you need to test me?
要对暗号吗
Girls change a lot, right?
由于女大十大变嘛
I almost
实在是有点
couldn't recognize you.
认不出来你了
So this is just to be safe,
所以这个为了安全起见
I have to test you.
我得好好考考你
Your game password is
你的游戏密码是
2222.
二二二二
And my...
那我的
Your bank card password
你的银行卡密码
is also 2222.
也是二二二二
I...
我
Your phone password
你的手机密码
is 2222.
更是二二二二
All your passwords
你所有的密码
are 2222.
都是二二二二
Only you would
只有你会设
use such silly passwords.
这么二的密码
Li'l Su, it's really you.
苏小妹 真的是你啊
Well, you can't blame me.
那不是我说你啊
Don't you think
你这身打扮
your outfit is too much?
是不是有点太夸张了
I'm telling you,
我跟你说
madam Chang Xiuying
咱们家常秀英女士
is a quite traditional
还是比较传统的
Chinese OG.
中国老太太
But look at you,
但你这样的话
you're too showy.
你这么夸张的话
Remember to talk properly,
你等会儿说话要收敛点
behave yourself,
你不能指手画脚的
and don't talk like rapping,
跟人说话跟唱说唱一样
or you'll scare her.
这样她会吓到的
Are you listening?
你有听我说话吗
C'mon, got it!
知道了 知道了
I'll get changed.
你等我换个装
Grandma.
外婆
Li'l Su, you're back.
小妹来了
Grandma, I missed you so much!
外婆 想死你了
Li'l Su,
小妹啊
well,
哎呦
I missed you too.
外婆也想你哟
Dad,
爸
Grandma,
还有奶奶呀
she is
人家现在
not Li'l Su anymore,
不流行叫苏小妹了
you should call her Susie.
人家流行叫苏夕 洋气
No,
不不不
I love
我可喜欢
being called Li'l Su,
别人叫我小妹了
it's so endearing.
多亲切呀
Let me have a look at you.
叫外婆看看你
You've grown taller and prettier.
长高了 更加漂亮了
Such a beautiful young lady now.
水灵灵一个大姑娘喽
Li'l Su,
小妹啊
you've really changed a lot.
真是女大十八变啊
Yeah.
是啊
Why did you
你这怎么回事
suddenly come back?
忽然就跑过来了
You didn't even call.
也不打个电话
I could have picked you up.
我好去接你
You've been away for long, huh?
有日子没来湘北了吧
Stay a few more days
多待两天
and keep your Grandma company.
在家里边好好陪陪外婆
She's missed you.
外婆可想你了
If you need anything,
有什么事啊
contact Jinghui.
你就找你表哥
Dad, no way.
爸 不行
I'm so busy.
我有事 我没空
No worries.
没事 舅舅
I'll definitely keep in touch with him,
就算表哥不愿意陪我
whether he's willing or not.
我也会缠着他的
Okay.
行
If he bullies you,
他要是敢欺负你
tell me,
跟舅舅说
and I'll deal with him.
看我怎么收拾他
Dad, do you think that's possible?
爸 谁欺负谁啊
Let's go.
走走走
Li'l Su,
小妹啊
I'll show you to your room.
我带你看你房间去
Jinghui, thank you for helping me carry
那这些行李就拜托表哥
my luggage upstairs.
帮我搬上去了
When did I agree
我什么时候答应你
to do that?
把这些行李搬上楼了
Grandma, it's too heavy for me.
外婆 人家搬不动嘛
Jinghui,
小灰啊
just help your sister.
你就帮帮你妹妹嘛
She's a delicate girl.
人家是柔弱的女孩
As a boy,
男孩啊
you should take care of her.
照顾一下也是应该的嘛
Yeah, exactly.
是呀 是呀
Let's go.
走
Li'l Su,
苏小妹
what's
你这里面都装的
in your suitcase?
什么东西啊
Weights? It's so heavy.
秤砣吗 这么重
Be careful.
你小心点
Those are my treasures.
那都是我的宝贝
Jesus. You eat
你一大小伙子
3 bowls of rice every meal,
一顿饭吃三碗干饭
how heavy can it be?
这一箱子能多沉哪
It's not that heavy.
这不也不沉吗
Carry it up.
抬上去
Dad. Dad!
爸 爸
Why did you just toss it?
你怎么能把这个乱扔啊
I didn't toss it.
我哪儿乱扔了
I put it on the bed.
我这不放床上了吗
My Estée Lauder,
我的小棕瓶
so cute.
真可爱
My SK-II,
还有我的神仙水
and my Chanel.
还有我的小香香
What are these?
这都什么跟什么呀
You know nothing
你懂什么呀
These are worth
我这些宝贝
more than your game consoles.
够买你那好几个游戏机
My babies,
我的小可爱
you're finally home now
跟我一路颠簸
after a long journey.
辛苦你们了
Alright, alright.
行了 行了 行了啊
Stop wiping.
别擦了
It's already clean.
那上面干净成这样
What's there to wipe?
有什么可擦的
Hurry
快快快
and clean up.
赶紧收拾收拾
We're going out.
出去
Where to?
干嘛去
Madam Chang Xiuying
常秀英女士
gave me a task
交代的任务嘛
to take you out for shopping
带你出去逛街
and having fun.
吃喝玩乐
I'm not going.
我不去了
I'm jet-lagged.
我倒时差
Go by yourself.
你一个人去吧
You flew from Singapore.
你从新加坡飞过来的
Do you need to deal with jet lag?
你需要倒时差吗
I don't want to go.
我不想去 不想去
I want to watch shows.
我要追剧了
You said it.
这可是你说的啊
I'm going out with friends.
我要跟朋友去玩了啊
Don't go snitching
别去那常秀英女士那儿
to her.
告我状啊
I won't.
不会 不会
Explain it yourself.
自己去解释啊
Go ahead.
你去吧 去吧
Don't worry about me.
不用管我
Really?
是真的啊
Bye.
拜拜
Hello?
喂
Everything goes well.
一切顺利
Don't worry.
放心吧
Just leave it to me.
这点小事包在我身上
I've got it all planned.
我都已经计划好了
I'll go to his room later
等会儿就去他的房间
and take care of it.
把这件事给办了
Okay.
嗯
Jinghui?
表哥
Why...
你 你
Why are you here?
你怎么在这儿啊
Why am I here?
我怎么会在这儿
This is my room.
这是我房间
You tell me.
你说呢
Where else would I be?
那不然我在哪儿
Aren't you going out
你 你不是要跟朋友
with friends?
一起去玩吗
I am, right now.
我这不正玩着吗
Aren't you going to watch shows?
你不说要看剧吗
Why are you here?
在这儿干嘛呢
Yeah,
对呀
watching shows.
看 看剧
I...
我
just...
这 这不
don't know the Wi-Fi password.
不知道无线网密码吗
What's the Wi-Fi password?
无线网密码多少
I'll text it to you.
这事 手机发给你
Why aren't you leaving?
你咋还不走
I'm leaving.
走 走
I'm telling you,
我告诉你啊
don't bother me while I'm studying.
别打扰我学习
Are you studying?
你这哪是学习
You're playing games.
你这是玩游戏
Can't I study while gaming?
玩游戏不能学习啊
I can learn in games.
在游戏中进步
I'll teach you.
我教你
I'll help you level up.
我带你上分
Really?
真的
No, thanks.
不需要
I can really teach you.
我真的可以教
Thank you.
谢谢你啊
Your mom's recovery is going well.
你妈恢复得不错
Doctor,
医生
what should we
回去之后
watch out for when we go back?
还有什么需要注意的吗
Overall,
总体来说呢
she's doing fine.
已经没有什么大碍了
Just remember
回去之后呢
to rest more and
注意多休息
don't be tired.
不要劳累
If there's
如果再察觉到
any discomfort with the heart,
心脏不舒服的时候啊
come for another check-up.
就来医院做检查就行了
See, I told you.
你看我就说吧
I'm fine.
没什么事
No need for a follow-up.
都不用来复查的
Mom,
妈
health isn't something to be careless about.
身体这事可不能马虎
Your son is right.
您儿子说得对
Better safe than sorry.
不怕一万就怕万一
Yes.
是
Okay.
那行
Doctor, we're leaving.
医生 我们先走了
Thank you.
谢谢你啊
You're welcome.
好嘞 不客气
Thanks, Doctor.
谢谢医生
Goodbye.
再见啊
Bye.
再见
See, nothing to worry about.
我就说嘛 啥事都没有
You're just
你看你这孩子
too tense.
太紧张了
Mom, just take care.
妈 还是注意一点
I will, don't worry.
好好好 放心吧
Let's go home and have dinner.
妈回家给你做好吃的
Jinghui,
哥
I think your room
我觉得你这个房间
is great.
非常地好
Look at the layout, the decor,
你看这格局 这摆设
and the lighting,
关键是这个采光
I like it.
我喜欢
Your room isn't different
你的房间跟我的房间
from mine.
没差别
This guy is handsome.
这小哥哥好帅啊
I know.
我知道
Make it clear,
你给我说清楚了
him or me?
是他还是我
In the photo,
照片上
am I not more handsome?
难道我不比他帅吗
Yeah, you're the most handsome.
帅 你最帅了
Your bed...
你这个床
is so hard.
好硬啊
I like sleeping on hard beds.
我就喜欢睡硬的床
Stop talking nonsense.
能别胡说八道了吗
Your bed is the same
你的床跟我的床
as mine.
一模一样
Your room
你这个房间
is really nice.
环境特别的好
What do you want?
到底要干嘛呀
Can I...
我
Can I switch rooms
我可以跟你
with you, Jinghui?
换个房间睡吗 表哥
Wait and see,
我就不信
I will handle this.
搞不定你这条二哈了
Be careful.
慢点
Finally home.
终于回来了
Mom, want an orange?
妈 吃橘子吗
I'll peel it for you.
妈妈给你 我来剥
Sit down.
坐吧
Okay.
好
Dong,
冬冬啊
what's your birthday wish?
你的生日愿望是什么
Mom,
妈
didn't I tell you before?
我不是跟你说过了吗
I know,
我知道
I just want you
妈妈就是想
to say it again.
让你再说一遍嘛
My wish is for you
我的生日愿望就是
to always be healthy,
希望你能一直健康
so I can always be with you.
我也能一直陪在你身边
See,
你看啊
your wish has
你的生日愿望啊
come true.
灵验了
You just heard it.
你不是听医生说了嘛
The doctor said I'm fine.
医生说妈妈没什么事了
Everything's good.
都挺好的了
I want to discuss something with you.
妈妈想跟你商量个事
Mom,
妈
don't bother.
不用商量了
We've
志愿的事
talked about the college.
咱们之前也是聊过的
Well,
不是
I know you're being filial.
妈妈知道你这份孝心
You can choose to stay.
你呢 可以选择留下来
It's your choice.
那是你的选择
I respect that.
妈妈尊重你
But I just wanna
那我就是想
discuss with you
跟你商量一下
whether I can go to
我可不可以
JU with you.
去京大陪着你
I wanna see you there
我想看着你进京大
and achieve success.
我想看见我儿子有出息
It will make me happier.
我会更开心
I don't want to regret it.
我不想有这个遗憾
I'll always
你在哪儿
be by your side.
那妈妈就在哪儿
A house is not a home.
房子吧 不是家
Home is where you are.
只有人才是
What do you say?
你说呢
Mom...
妈
Happy birthday!
生日快乐
Ling Dong, happy birthday.
凌冬 生日快乐
This is for you.
这个给你
Your wish at eighteen
十八岁的愿望
will come true.
一定会实现
Ling Dong,
凌冬
may all your wishes come true,
祝你未来所求皆所愿
and may your path be smooth.
所行化坦途